在传说中的时代里
In a land of myth and a time of magic,
王国的命运
the destiny of a great kingdom
肩负在一个年轻男孩的身上
rests on the shoulders of a young boy.
他的名字...梅林
His name...Merlin
梅林! 矛
Merlin! Spear.
天生就这么一无是处 梅林?
Do you have any natural gifts, Merlin?
当然不是
No.
让我想想
Let me think...
也不是天生就这么粗鲁愚钝啦
I'm not naturally rude or insensitive.
不过是天生惹人怒罢了
Just naturally irritating.
也许它比你还恐惧
It's probably more scared of you than you are of it.
我们甩掉它了?       谁掉队了?
Have we lost it?        Who's missing?
贝蒂威尔骑士在哪?
Where's Sir Bedivere?
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=破烂熊字幕组=-
翻译：麦麦 奈奈 多多 库库
校对&时间轴：麦麦
录制:chocolate
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
梅林传奇 第1季第13集
你口中所描述的那生物的所有特征
The creature you describe has all the characteristics
都跟寻水兽相符     那不过是个传说
of the Questing Beast.        Surely that's a myth.
据史书记载
accroding to the old books of
寻水兽的出现
the appearance of the Questing Beast
预示着一次剧变的到来
is supposed to foreshadow a time of great upheaval.
盖尤斯 那不过是老妇人的故事
Gaius, that's an old wives' tale.
管它是什么 现在大家被它搞得人心惶惶
Look, whatever it is, it is spreading panic.
人们害怕它会闯入这里
The people fear it will enter the city.
我们得了结它
Then we must kill it.
亚瑟 准备人马 我们破晓出发
Arthur, gather the guard together. We ride at dawn
求你了 陛下 别小看此兽 这是一个预兆
I beg you, Sire.do not dismiss this. The beast is an omen
我以前见过它
I have seen it come before,
就在您夫人艾葛兰死前那晚
the night your wife Ygraine passed away
告诉过你别再提那晚上的事了
I've told you not to speak of that night again.
我早就征服了古教
I have conquered the Old Religion.
它的警告对我不起作用
Its warnings mean nothing to me now.
等亚瑟灭掉那畜生
Arthur will destroy the beast
我们就不必再受其折磨了
and we no longer suffer at its hand.
这次不是普通的怪兽 梅林
This is no ordinary beast, Merlin.
别担心      不 听我说 你不明白
Don't worry.        No, listen to me. You don't understand.
乌瑟不相信古教 但一切都是真的
Uther may not respect the Old Religion, but it is very real.
知彼知己
To face a beast such as this,
方能百战不殆
you must understand where it came from.
你什么意思?      在古教的中心
What do you mean?        At the very heart of the Old Religion
蕴藏着生死魔法的本源
lies the magic of life and death itself.
寻水兽拥有那个力量
The Questing Beast carries that power.
咬上一口 你就没命了
One bite, you die.
无药可救
And there is no cure.
莫嘉娜! 莫嘉娜!
Morgana! Morgana!
醒醒!      不! 不!
Wake up!        No! No!
是我 是歌薇啊!醒醒 那不过是一场梦
It's me, it's Gwen! Stop it. It was just another dream.
太可怕了      没事了
It was terrifying.        It's all right.
你们已经见过敌人了
You've seen the foe we face.
那是一只可怕的怪兽
It's a creature of nightmare
但你们是王国里数一数二的骑士
But you are the best knights in the realm.
王国的子民受到伤害之前
We can and will kill it,
我们得干掉它
before it harms another citizen of our kingdom.
为对甘美洛的爱!
For the love of Camelot!
亚瑟!
Arthur!
莫嘉娜 你来干什么?      你不能去
Morgana, what are you doing?        You cannot face it!
莫嘉娜 回去睡你的觉
Morgana, go back to bed.
没什么好怕的
There is nothing to be afraid of.
求你了 亚瑟 我看到些可怕的东西
Please, Arthur. I have seen terrible things.
你不能去      她可能做噩梦了 殿下
You cannot go.        She's probably had a bad dream, Sire.
我让盖尤斯给她看看     不 我不能让你去!
I'll take her to see Gaius.        No, I will not let you go!
帮帮忙 梅林 把她拉进去      不!
Please, Merlin, get her inside.        No!
小姐 我会确保他的安全 我答应你      不!不!
I will make sure he is safe, my lady. I promise.        No! No!
跟着足迹走
Let's follow the trail.
跟紧点
Keep close.
是什么?
What is it?
喂
Hey!
(咒语)
Fleoge. Bregdan anwiele gefeluec!
它没咬中你 对吧?
It didn't bite you, did it?
亚瑟!
Arthur!
来人啊 救命啊!
Somebody help me!
发生什么事了?
What's happened?
他被咬了!      我试过救他
He's been bitten!         I tried to save him.
我们得禀告国王
We must tell the King.
你一定有办法的
There must be something you can do.
我也希望有      我找找疗法
I wish there was.        I'll find a cure.
梅林!      相信我
Merlin!        Trust me.
你能听到我吗?殿下
Can you hear me, Sire?
这里
Here.
国外随时会到      他不能死
The King will be here any moment.        He can't die.
我的宿命是保护他
It is my destiny to protect him.
我们还没做过该做的事呢
We haven't done all the things we're meant to do!
这是所有人的哀痛      盖尤斯 他是我的朋友
That is the lament of all men.        Gaius, he's my friend.
那就拯救他
Then save him.
(咒语)
Gethlio!
Thurhaele!
也许咒语需要一点时间来发挥效用
Maybe the spells need time to take effect.
寻水兽的撕咬判定生死
The bite of the Questing Beast is a death sentence
没有魔法能逆转
that no magic can overturn.
我的儿子在哪?亚瑟!
Where is my son? Arthur!
想办法啊 盖尤斯!
Do something, Gaius!
我正在努力 陛下
I am trying, Your Majesty.
盖尤斯会找到疗法 不会让他死去的
Gaius will find a cure. He will not let him die.
我会使劲浑身解数
I will do everything in my power.
我把他送回房间
I will bear him to his chamber.
我已经失去了亚瑟 我的使命已经失败了
I have failed Arthur,failed in my destiny.
如果真是这样的话 你不会来这里
And yet, you would not be here if that were true.
他被寻水兽咬到了
He was bitten by the Questing Beast.
他会死
He's going to die.
他还有呼吸吗?
Does he still breathe?
一息尚存      那么还有时间治愈他
Only just.         Then there is still time to heal him.
我试过了 但救不了他
I've tried, I cannot save him.
你不知道怎么救他
You do not know how to save him.
但你能告诉我 是吗?
But you can tell me how?
也许
Perhaps.
可不是那么容易的
It will not be easy.
我愿意做任何事      任何事?
I will do anything.        Anything?
求你了 告诉我该怎么做吧!
Please. Just tell me what I have to do!
很好
Very well.
寻水兽是利用古教的魔力
The Questing Beast is a creature
召唤出来的神兽
conjured by the powers of the Old Religion.
你也要用同样的远古魔法来救他
You must use the same ancient magic to save him.
古教几百年前已经消亡
The Old Religion died out centuries ago.
古教就是土地本身的魔力
The Old Religion is the magic of the earth itself.
是将万物聚合在一起的原素
It is the essence which binds all things together.
会延续得比人类还长久
It will last long beyond the time of men.
这些和我救亚瑟有什么联系?
But how can that help me save Arthur?
你要找到仍然侍奉这种力量的人
You must find those who still serve it.
操控人们生死的人
Those who hold dominion over life and death.
哪里?
Where?
前往人们称为祈愿岛的地方
Go to the place that men call the Isle of the Blessed,
远古力量在那里仍然存在
where the power of the ancients can still be felt.
你在那里能找到拯救亚瑟的办法
There you will discover Arthur's salvation.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢      梅林
Thank you.        And Merlin
小潘达贡必须活着 不管要付出多大的代价
the young Pendragon must live, no matter what the cost.
梅林 你回来了
Merlin, you're back.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我们得把这个带给亚瑟 让他去得安详点
We must get this to Arthur to ease his passing.
不 我们要救他      我们已经试过了
No. We have to save him.        We've already tried.
那神兽出自古教
The Beast comes from the Old Religion
解法也应当出自那里
the cure must come from there as well.
通晓这些的人为数不多了
There are few left with such an art.
你说过古教依然存在
You said yourself that the Old Religion still alive,and...
在白山附近有个岛...       不!
There is an island beyond the white mountains...         No!
祈愿岛 你知道?
The Isle of the Blessed - you know it?
据说那里是古教的中心
It was said to be the centre of the Old Religion,
凝聚了所有的力量
the focus of its power.
你为什么不告诉我?
Why did you keep this from me?
因为太危险了 梅林
Because it was too dangerous, Merlin.
这是我们唯一的机会!
It's our only chance!
我一定要找到它!
I have to find it.
一旦你到达那里 你要祈求什么?
And once you are there, what will you ask?
祈求亚瑟得救
For Arthur to be saved.
寻水兽选中了亚瑟
The Questing Beast chose Arthur.
意味着古教决定了他的命运
That means the Old Religion has decided his fate.
那我就劝服他们改变主意
Then I will convince them to change their minds.
没那么容易!
It is not that simple!
大祭司拥有镜像生命和死亡的能力
The high priests have the power to mirror life and death.
但要付出代价
But there will be a price to pay.
要一命换一命
They will demand a life in return.
梅林 别那样 我恳求你...
Merlin, please, I beg of you...
我很抱歉 盖尤斯
I'm sorry, Gaius.
但无论代价是什么 我都愿意承受
But whatever the price is, I will pay it gladly.
给你 你需要地图
Here. You'll need a map.
还有这个 给你
And I'm going to give you this.
我母亲给我的
My mother gave it to me.
是兔子腿
It's a rabbit's foot.
保佑你平安?
To keep you safe?
据说能保护人类免受邪灵的袭击
It was said to protect you from evil spirits.
是废物啦 我不信这些迷信的东西
It's rubbish. I don't believe the superstition.
我不知道我为什么要给你
I don't know why I gave it to you. No.
我想要
I want it.
谢谢
Thank you.
在我回来之前 你要让亚瑟好好活着
You've got to keep Arthur alive until I get back.
睡吧 亚瑟
Sleep, Arthur.
你要前往
You must travel to the place
人们称为祈愿岛的地方
that men call the Isle of the Blessed,
在白山后面
'beyond the white mountains,
穿过王落谷
through the Valley of the Fallen Kings.
在梅里铎之海的北边
'To the north of the Great Seas of Meredor,
会找到一个湖
you will find a lake.'
盖尤斯
Gaius.
你该休息一下
You should get some rest.
他需要有人照看
He must not be left alone.
我会照顾他
I will nurse him.
你不可以死 亚瑟 我在跟你说话呢
You're not going to die, Arthur. I'm telling you.
因为我知道有一天 你会成为国王
Because I know that one day, you will be King,
远胜于你父亲的伟大君主
a greater king than your father could ever be.
那是我活下去的动力
It's what keeps me going.
你要活着 成为我期望看到的人 亚瑟
You are going to live to be the man I've seen inside you, Arthur
让我看到卡美洛变得平等公正
I can see a Camelot that is fair and just.
让我看到人们爱戴
I can see a king that the people will love
自豪地奉为君主的人
and be proud to call their sovereign.
为了对卡美洛的爱...
For the love of Camelot...
你必须活下去
you have to live.
我能给你拿点什么吗?陛下
Is there anything I can get Your Majesty?
人们开始告别
The people have begun to say goodbye.
他还没死 陛下      但他不会复原了
He is not yet gone, Sire.        But he will not recover.
除非有奇迹发生
Not without a miracle.
我不相信奇迹
I don't believe in miracles.
(咒语)
Astyre!
有人吗?
Hello?
你好 梅林
Hello, Merlin.
是你?
You?
你知道我是谁?      妮摩薇
Do you know who I am?        Nimueh.
你不会是神龙说的那人
You can't be who the Dragon meant.
为什么这么说?
And why is that?
你想杀我
You tried to kill me.
那是在我意识到你有多重要之前
Before I understood your importance.
而亚瑟...
And Arthur...
亚瑟命不该绝于我手中
Arthur was never destined to die at my hand.
而现在 看来我成了他的救星
And now, it seems I will be his salvation.
那你知道我为何而来?
So you know what I've come to ask?
是的       你愿意这么做吗?
Yes.        Will you do it?
我没有强大到
I do not have the power
能复制生命而什么都不索取
to mirror life itself and yet give nothing in return.
我知道会有代价的
I know a price will be asked.
要拯救一条生命 必然要有人送命
To save a life, there must be a death.
世界的平衡必须被复原
The balance of the world must be restored.
我愿意用自己一命来换亚瑟的
I willingly give my life for Arthur's.
真勇敢啊 梅林
How brave you are, Merlin.
如果能这么简单的话
If only it were that simple.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
一旦进入交易 那就必须完成
Once you enter into this bargain, it cannot be undone.
无论做什么 我都愿意
Whatever I have to do, I will do.
他的命抵我的百倍
His life is worth a hundred of mine.
生命之杯
The Cup of Life,
由千百年来的强大法术庇佑
blessed by centuries of powerful sorcery
它承载着生命的秘密
so that it contains the very secret of life itself.
如果亚瑟能喝到杯中之水... 那他便能活过来
If Arthur drinks water from the cup...he will live.
(咒语)
Tidrenas!
交易已经达成
The bargain is struck.
我希望它会令你满意
I hope it pleases you.
梅林      我们要把这个给亚瑟
Merlin!         We need to give this to Arthur.
这是什么     水 取自生命之杯
What is it?        Water, drawn from the Cup of Life.
如果亚瑟喝了这个他就会复活 快点
If Arthur drinks from it, he will recover. Please hurry!
你还在等什么
What are you waiting for?
你用什么偿还他的生命
What price did you pay to redeem his life?
你用谁的命做交易
Whose life did you bargain?
我们没时间了      梅林
We don't have time.         Merlin!
别担心 盖尤斯 一切都会好的
Don't worry, Gaius, everything's going to be all right.
你在做什么 御医? 你给他的是什么
What are you doing, physician? What are you giving him?
这是 呃...
It's, er...
是药剂 由半边莲制成
It's a tincture, made from the lobelia plant.
一个治疗毒物咬伤的古老方剂
An ancient remedy for poisonous bites.
能治愈?
A cure?
但愿吧
We hope.
你真的觉得这会有效?
Do you really think it will have some effect?
这是我们仅有的办法了 殿下
It's our last resort, Sire.
也许您该让他休息一下
Perhaps you should allow him to rest.
我不会离开他的
I will not leave him.
拜托 梅林 你一定要小心
Please, Merlin, you must beware.
一切刚刚开始
This is only the beginning.
亚瑟!
Arthur!
王子活过来了
The Prince lives.
我以为失去你了
I thought we'd lost you.
别担心 父王 我不会死的
Don't worry, Father, I'm not going to die.
我想一定有人在关照我 让我远离死亡
I think there's someone watching over me,keeping me from her.
也许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
在你漫长的王者之路上
On your long journey to become King,
需要一个守护天使
you'll need a guardian angel.
我要去皇宫昭告他们的王子复活了
I shall inform the court that their Prince lives.
我就知道
I knew it.
我说过你会没事的
I said you'd be all right.
我记得你和我说过话
I can remember you talking to me.
你记得?      你抚摸着我的额头
You can?         You stroked my forehead.
我在测你的体温      永不要失去信心
I was tending to your fever.       Never lost faith.
我只是说说      再告诉我一次你说话
I was just talking.         Tell me again what you said.
我不记得了
I don't remember.
你当然记得
Yes, you do.
不 我忘了       来嘛
No, I don't.         Come on.
关于什么我内心是怎样的男人
Something about the man I am inside.
不 我从未说过这些        歌妮薇
No, I never said that.        Guinevere!
我得去洗这些了 殿下
I have to get these washed, Sire.
盖尤斯
Gaius!
我还活着 是怎么回事? 发生了什么?
I'm alive! What is it? What's happened?
梅林 呆在那
Merlin, stay there.
怎么回事
What's wrong?
不 别过来
No, don't.
妈妈?
Mother?
梅林
Merlin...
她怎么了?      她病得很严重
What's happened to her?         She's gravely ill.
做些什么!      如果我能的话...
Do something!        If I could...
拜托了 盖尤斯
Please, Gaius.
梅林 这不是一般的疾病
Merlin, this is no ordinary illness.
这不该发生的!
This cannot happen!
你去祈愿岛见的谁?
Who did you meet at the Isle of the Blessed?
妮摩薇
Nimueh.
妮摩薇?!       就是她
Nimueh?!         It was as you said.
她要回报
She demanded a price.
我用自己的生命做交易 而不是我母亲的
But I bargained my life, not my mother's!
梅林 我希望能做些什么
Merlin, I wish there was something I could do.
我会让你好起来的 我会的
I will make you better. I will.
你知道这会发生的
You knew this would happen!
你让我用自己母亲的性命换亚瑟的
You had me trade my mother's life for Arthur's!
你说过会做任何事
You said you would do anything.
你知道我妈妈会死吗?
Did you know my mother would die?
我知道这条性命的分量非比寻常
I knew the price would be a heavy one.
但你还是要我去了
But you sent me anyway.
我们需要亚瑟活着
We need Arthur to live.
我不是你们中的一员!
I'm not one of you!
我们都是古教的产物
We are both creatures of the Old Religion.
这是你的力量之源
It is the source of your power.
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你的宿命便是保护年轻的潘达贡
Your destiny is to protect the young Pendragon
直到他加上皇冕
until he claims his crown.
而当他封王 魔法便会重回大地
And when he does, magic can be returned to the realm.
只有那样我才会重获自由
Only then will I be free.
这就是你所关心全部?
So that's all you cared about?
我以为你是我的朋友
I thought you were my friend.
我不只是你的朋友 梅林
I am more than that, Merlin.
我是你的亲人
I am your kin.
不 我唯一的亲人就是我妈妈
No, the only family I have is my mother,
而你还让我害死了她
and you had me murder her.
她的性命不是白白丢掉的
Her life has not been taken in vain.
我们一起会共创伟业 你和我
We will achieve great things together, you and I.
你永远不会被释放
You will never be release.
因为你的所作所为 我保证不会让你重见光明
For what you've done, I'll make sure you never see the light.
梅林
Merlin!
你... 不会再见到我了
You...won't see me...again.
她在哪?
Where is she?
她还在睡
She's sleeping.
我一定要救她      你没办法
I have to save her.         You cannot.
如果世界需要一条生命来平衡
If the balance of the world needs a life,
那就让歌妮薇把我的取走
then Nimueh must take mine.
不 梅林
No, Merlin.
是的 我要回到岛上
Yes. I will return to the island.
你还年轻 你的天赋 你的宿命
You are young. Your gifts, your destiny,
比自我牺牲珍贵得多
are far too precious to sacrifice.
我的宿命? 这是我母亲
My destiny? This is my mother.
如果不能救她那我的法力一无是处
My powers mean nothing if I cannot save her.
你教会了我许多
You have taught me so much.
你教会我认识自我 教会我法术的用途
You taught me who I am, taught me the purpose for my skills,
教会我魔法只能用在该用的地方
taught me that magic should only be used for great deeds.
最重要的是 你一直教导我...
But most of all, you have always taught me...
要做正确的事情
to do what is right.
梅林...
Merlin...
我要去向亚瑟告别
I need to say goodbye to Arthur.
啊 梅林      你怎么样?
Ah, Merlin.        How are you?
很好
Good.
我为你高兴
I'm pleased.
是啊
Yes.
多亏了盖尤斯
I owe it all to Gaius.
我有事要跟你说
I need to talk to you.
你还是不理解 是吧?
You still haven't got it yet, have you?
我想谈的时候才能谈
I decide when we need to talk.
今天不行
Not today.
有时候我都怀疑你知不知道我是谁
I sometimes wonder if you know who I am.
哦 我知道你是谁
Oh, I know who you are.
很好
Good.
你是个混蛋
You're a prat.
皇家混蛋
And a royal one.
你怎样也改不了吗 梅林?
Are you ever going to change, Merlin?
不会 会让你厌倦的
No. You'd get bored.
请你保证如果再找仆人的话
Promise me this, if you get another servant,
不要找那种只会拍马屁的
don't get a bootlicker.
如果你这是想请辞...      不
If this is you trying to leave your job...          No.
我很乐意做你的仆人 直到我生命终结的那一天
I'm happy to be your servant, till the day I die.
有时候我觉得我挺了解你的 梅林
Sometimes I think I know you, Merlin.
而也有些时候...      我了解你
Other times...        Well, I know you.
你是个伟大的勇士
And you're a great warrior.
将来有一天你会成为伟大的国王
One day you will be a great king.
承蒙夸奖
That's very kind of you.
但你在学着作战的同时也必须要学会听进忠言
But you must learn to listen as well as you fight.
还有其它指教吗?
Any other pointers?
没有了
No.
就这些
That's it.
只是...
Just...
别做一个混蛋
don't be a prat.
盖尤斯去拿一些补给品了
Gaius had to go and get some supplies.
他让我看着她 等你回来
He asked me to keep an eye on her until you got back.
谢谢你
Thank you.
我很难过      不 她会好起来的
I'm sorry.       No, she'll get better.
我尽量让她感到舒适一些
I've tried to make her feel comfortable.
你有着一颗善良的心 歌薇
You've such a good heart, Gwen.
永远不要丢弃
Don't ever lose that.
我会让你好起来的 我保证
I'm gonna make you well again. I promise.
你会看到的
You'll see.
你真是个好孩子
You're such a good son.
但我不想让你为我担心
But I don't want you to worry about me.
我知道神灵会眷顾我
I know that the Gods will look after me
有一天 我们会再见面的
and that one day, I will see you again.
我会想你的
I will miss you.
我也会想你的
I'll miss you, too.
盖尤斯
Gaius?
亲爱的梅林
'Dear Merlin,
我的生命已经快要走到尽头
'my life is already near to its end.
我一生的大部分时间里 都过得毫无意义
'There has, for the most part, been very little purpose to it.
没有太多值得被怀念
'Very little that will be remembered.
相比之下 梅林 你注定拥有伟大的一生
'In contrast, Merlin, your life is destined for greatness.
遵循我教过你的原则
'Live by the tenets I have taught you,
我相信假以时日
'and I believe you will, in time,
你一定会成为最伟大的魔法师
become the greatest warlock ever.
认识你是我最大的荣幸
'To have known you has been my greatest pleasure,
为你牺牲对我来说是种荣耀
'and to sacrifice myself for you is but an honour.
你永远都是我的孩子
'You are, and will always be, the son I never had.'
不要!
No!
我从来没想过我们会再次在此会面
I never thought I'd see you here again.
夫人
My Lady.
你很久没有这么叫我了
It is a long time since you called me that.
我是来请求你的帮助的
I've come to ask for your help.
就像你上次为乌瑟做的一样吗
As you once did before, for Uther.
你并不喜欢那个结果
You did not like the outcome.
我给你一个为他妻子之死赎罪的机会
I offer a chance for you to atone for the death of his wife.
我救过她儿子的性命
I have saved the life of her son.
你还想要怎样?
What more do you ask for?
这一次 我们做个公平的交易
That this time, you take a just price.
梅林想用他的生命换取他母亲的
Merlin intends to offer his life for his mother's.
我要你让我顶替他的位置
I want you to take mine in his place.
尽我所有预言的能力
With all my powers of prediction,
我也无法预知到这些
I could never have foretold this.
英雄盖尤斯
Gaius the hero!
我为何要答应你的请求?
Why should I grant your wish?
你眼睁睁地看着我们的朋友们
You stood and watched as our friends
在大肃清行动中被活活烧死
burned in the Great Purge.
你就是一个叛徒
You are nothing but a traitor.
梅林是可以把魔法带回这片土地的人
Merlin is the one man who can bring magic back to this land.
在亚瑟身边 他可以协助建立一个新的王国
At Arthur's side, he can help forge a new kingdom.
一个我们梦寐以求的美丽安宁的世界
A world of peace and beauty that we can only dream of.
而你原意宁愿付出你的生命 盖尤斯
And you're willing to give your life, Gaius,
只为了他们所能造就的将来?
for the future they will bring?
我在等你的答案
I'm waiting.
你准备受死了吗 盖尤斯?
Are you ready to die, Gaius?
盖尤斯?
Gaius?
为了梅林 我原意献出我的生命
For Merlin, I will give my life.
(咒语)
Ic, seo heahsacerd, the acwelle strengthe ealdan aewfaestnesse!
住手!
Stop!
这么快就回来啦 魔法师?
Back again so soon, warlock?
你做了什么?
What have you done?
你母亲不会有事了
Your mother is safe.
这不是你想要的吗?
Isn't that what you wanted?
你杀了他吗?
Have you killed him?
这是他的愿望
It was his wish.
我用我的生命去换取亚瑟的生命 不是用我母亲或盖尤斯的
I bid my life for Arthur's, not my mother's, not Gaius'!
古教是不会在乎谁死谁活
The Old Religion does not care who lives or dies.
它只在乎世界的平衡得到维持
Only that the balance of the world is restored.
一命换一命 盖尤斯知道这个
To save a life, a life must be taken. Gaius knew this.
这不是古教的所为 而是你
It is not the Old Religion that has done this. It is you.
来吧
Come, now.
我们对彼此都有利用价值 做敌人太可惜
We are too valuable to each other to be enemies.
不 我跟你没有任何共同之处
No! I share nothing with you.
有了我的帮助 亚瑟会成为国王的
With my help, Arthur will become King.
我会让亚瑟成为国王的 但你永远也看不到
I will make Arthur King. But you will never see that day.
(咒语)
Astrice!
你这些小把戏对我没用 梅林
Your childish tricks are useless against me, Merlin.
我可是古教的女祭司
I am a priestess of the Old Religion.
(咒语)
Forbearne!
你也是古教的一个人材
You too are a creature of the Old Religion.
你我应该联手的
You should join me.
你以为我会跟自私
You think I would join forces with
而又残忍的魔法师联手吗?
such a selfish and cruel magic?
休想
Never.
那好吧
So be it. Akwele!
真可惜
Pity.
你我联手本可统治世界的
Together, we could have ruled the world.
你不该杀害我朋友的
You should not have killed my friend.
盖尤斯!
Gaius!
不! 不!
No-o-o! No-o-o!
梅林 梅林
Merlin... Merlin...
盖尤斯!
Gaius!
盖尤斯 你还活着
Gaius, you're alive!
你做了什么?
What did you do?
妮摩薇已经死了 世界的平衡已经得到恢复
Nimueh's dead. The balance of the world has been restored.
你真让我惊喜
You amaze me.
你已经掌握了生与死的力量
You've mastered the power of life and death itself.
我们将让你成为一名伟大的魔法师
We'll make a great warlock of you yet!
那你现在相信我了?
So you believe in me now?
我相信你... 只要...
Well, I would do...if...
只要你能...
if you could...
阻止这场讨厌的雨
stop this blasted rain!
梅林!
Merlin!
不!
No! Aaagh!
请与破烂熊一起期待精彩的下季到来
-==www.RagBear.com==-
Tpring Nelly Docherty 麦麦预祝大家圣诞快乐
破烂熊字幕组
欢迎加入
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd